3d-viewers.com 2018-12-26

# Privacy Policy

Last updated: August 7th, 2018

Soft Gold Ltd, CADSoftTools trademark (“CADSoftTools”, “we”, “us”, and “our”) are committed to protecting and respecting the privacy of individuals who interact with us, such as our websites visitors, customers, and business partners (“you” and “your”). This Privacy Policy covers the information we collect about you when you visit the websites [https://cadsofttools.com](https://cadsofttools.com/), [https://cadsofttools.de](https://cadsofttools.de/), [https://fr.cadsofttools.com](https://fr.cadsofttools.com/), [https://cadsofttools.ru](https://cadsofttools.ru/), [https://jp.cadsofttools.com](https://jp.cadsofttools.com/), [https://es.cadsofttools.com](https://es.cadsofttools.com/), [https://it.cadsofttools.com](https://it.cadsofttools.com/), [https://kr.cadsofttools.com](https://kr.cadsofttools.com/), [https://nl.cadsofttools.com](https://nl.cadsofttools.com/), [https://br.cadsofttools.com](https://br.cadsofttools.com/), [https://cn.cadsofttools.com](https://cn.cadsofttools.com/), [http://3d-viewers.com](http://3d-viewers.com/), [http://pltviewer.com](http://pltviewer.com/), [http://abviewer.com](http://abviewer.com/), [https://sharecad.org](https://sharecad.org/), [http://beta.sharecad.org](http://beta.sharecad.org/) (“Websites”), use our products and services (“Products”), or otherwise interact with CADSoftTools. This Privacy Policy also describes how we collect, use, maintain, disclose, and protect that information.

By accessing our Websites and/or using our Products, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy, please do not access and/or use our Websites and Products.

**What Information We Collect About You**

Personal information is information that can identify an individual or relates to an identifiable individual. We collect personal information and other information a) when you provide it to us, b) when you navigate through our Websites, and c) when other parties provide it to us, as further described below.

**Information You Provide to Us**

We collect personal information when you voluntarily provide it to us by:

  * filling in forms on our Websites;
  * contacting us via email, live chat, Skype, telephone;
  * completing a feedback form;
  * posting on our forum;
  * ordering one of our Products.

It may include your name, surname, address, email, phone number, job title, company name, payment information and other information relevant to the purpose of the communication. We also collect files that you send to us or load to our Websites, and records of our interaction with you.

**Information We Automatically Collect**

We automatically collect information when you navigate through our Websites or view our advertisements. It includes your unique device identifier, IP address or MAC address, information about your location, the device you are using, your browsing actions, traffic data, and other similar information. We also use cookies and other tracking technologies. For more information please see the **Cookies and similar technologies** section.

**Information We collect From Other Parties**

We may collect information from our advertising and business partners, and other third parties we work with. For example, we can get your name, email, address, and company name from our resellers when you order one of our Products via them.

We may combine information from these different sources for the purposes set forth in this Privacy Policy.

**How We Use Information We Collect**

We use collected information for the following purposes:

  * to deliver our Products;
  * to provide customer support and information you have requested;
  * to communicate with you about our Products;
  * to validate your identity to the extent necessary to perform our contract with you;
  * to monitor and improve the quality of our Products;
  * to generate registration information;
  * to promote our Products;
  * to make our ads more relevant to your interests;
  * to send you special offers and newsletters. Each time we send you marketing materials, we give you the option to unsubscribe.
  * to provide our Websites;
  * to personalize your browsing experience on our Websites;
  * to track the Websites usage statistics;
  * to support and protect our legitimate interests and legal rights;
  * to carry out our obligations and enforce our rights;
  * to fulfil any other purpose for which you provide it;
  * for any other purpose with your consent.

**Legal Basis for Processing Personal Information**

Our legal basis for processing your personal information depends on the personal information concerned, the specific context in which we collect it, and the purposes for which it is used. In general, we collect your personal information only where:

  * we need it to fulfil our obligations to you, including to provide you with the Products, and provide customer support;
  * it satisfies our legitimate interests which are balanced against your rights and freedoms;
  * you give us consent to do so for a specific purpose;
  * we need it to process your personal information to comply with laws and regulations.

**How We Share Information We Collect**

We may share information about you with our service providers, business and advertising/marketing partners who need access to it in order to perform their tasks and duties. Any collected information is never sold to advertisers or other third parties. We may disclose any collected information, if it is necessary a) to comply with applicable law, regulation, legal process or governmental request, b) to enforce our agreements and terms of services, c) to respond to an emergency when we have a good faith that the disclosure is necessary to prevent illegal activities, d) to protect the rights, property, and safety of our company and our customers. We may also disclose your personal information for any purpose with your consent.

The aggregated information about our users, and information that does not identify any individual may be disclosed without restriction.

**How We Store and Secure Information We Collect**

**Storage**

We store your personal information on our servers and the servers of our service providers. Because we and our service providers maintain servers in global locations, your personal information may be stored, processed and transferred outside your home country, including in the Russian Federation, for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy. The level of data protection in such countries may not be deemed adequate by the European Commission. Therefore, we will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your personal information is treated securely.

**Data Retention Periods**

We keep your information only so long as we need it to provide you with the Products you are using and fulfill the purposes described in this Privacy Policy. When we no longer need to use your information and there is no need for us to keep it to comply with our legal or regulatory obligations, we will either remove it from our systems or depersonalize it so that we cannot identify you.

All files that you load while using the free online PDF to DWG converter (https://cadsofttools.com/pdf-to-dwg-online) and/or our Websites ([https://sharecad.org](https://sharecad.org/), [http://beta.sharecad.org](http://beta.sharecad.org/)) are stored for one month.

**Data Security**

We treat the security of your personal information with the utmost seriousness and provide reasonable means of security to protect data from illegal access, alteration and disclosure. However, since none of the means of protecting is 100% effective we cannot ensure the absolute security of the personal information.

**How to Access and Control Your Information**

You have the right to access, update, delete, receive a copy of, or restrict our use of your personal information. You can also withdraw the consent to process your personal information. To perform these actions please send a request to [info@cadsofttools.com](mailto:info@cadsofttools.com). You have the right to lodge a complaint with your national Data Protection Authority or equivalent regulatory body. However, before doing so, we request you to contact us directly in order to give us an opportunity to resolve your concerns about privacy. You may opt out of receiving marketing materials from us by using the unsubscribe link within each email or by sending an email to [info@cadsofttools.com](mailto:info@cadsofttools.com). You may opt out of receiving personalized advertisements, to know more about it please visit [www.youronlinechoices.eu](https://www.youronlinechoices.eu/) and [optout.networkadvertising.org](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/).

**Cookies and Similar Technologies**

We use cookies and similar technologies on our Websites.

Cookies are small text files that are downloaded to a device in order to remember basic information about the user. They have many different purposes, but mainly, cookies help understand how the website is being used, store preferences and settings, provide interest-based advertising and generally improve the user browsing experience.

**What Cookies We Use and How We Use Them**

Strictly Necessary Cookies

These cookies are necessary for our Websites to work properly. They do not store any personal information. If you disable these cookies, it will not be possible to provide certain features and functionalities.

Cookie name | Type | Description  
---|---|---  
PHPSESSID   
ASP.NET_SessionId | First-party | Preservers your session state across page requests.  
phpbb3_n79gh_k   
phpbb3_n79gh_sid   
phpbb3_n79gh_u | First-party | Ensures the correct work of the forum.  
  
Functionality Cookies

These cookies allow the Websites to remember choices you make in order to improve the Websites usability and performance. For example, they remember your selection of language, text size. They do not personally identify you.

Cookie name | Type | Description  
---|---|---  
cultureKey   
_currentUICulture | First-party | Remembers the select of language.  
user_cookie_consent | First-party | Stores your consent to the usage of cookies.  
  
Performance Cookies

These cookies are used to monitor your behavior on the Websites. For example, they count visits and traffic sources, shows the most frequently visited pages. The collected information is used to improve the way how the Websites work. Cookies are collected in aggregate and not tied to an individual.

Cookie name | Type | Description  
---|---|---  
_ga   
_gid   
_gac   
_gat   
_utma   
_utmc   
_utmz | First-party | Used by Google Analytics to generate statistical data on how you use the Websites.  
jv_close_time_ToSurWDZl5   
jv_enter_ts_ToSurWDZl5   
jv_invitation_time_ToSurWDZl5   
jv_pages_count_ToSurWDZl5   
jv_refer_ToSurWDZl5   
jv_utm_ToSurWDZl5   
jv_visits_count_ToSurWDZl5 | First-party | Used by Jivosite to count visits, time spend on the Websites and other parameters that are necessary for the live chat to work properly.  
_ym_isad   
_ym_uid   
_ym_visorc | First-party | Used by Yandex Metrica to indicate your status (new or returning), version of the browser used, device make and model, session duration, number of pages viewed, landing pages, and other non-personal information.  
  
Third-party Cookies

We use third-party cookies from the following providers: [Google](https://policies.google.com/privacy), [Yandex](https://metrica.yandex.com/about/info/privacy-policy), [Jivosite](https://www.jivochat.com/privacy/), [Youtube](https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/7671399), [AddThis](https://www.addthis.com/privacy). The purpose of these cookies is to collect information about your browsing and/or deliver advertising that is relevant to your interests. We do have neither access nor possibility to control the third-party cookies. Please consult the privacy policies on the respective providers’ websites for more information regarding their usage of the collected information.

**How to Control Cookies**

Most web browsers accept cookies by default but provide controls that allow you to disable or delete them. The exact procedure depends on the browser being used. Here are some specific examples for ease of reference, but please check the companies’ respective websites for the latest information:

Please note that disabling of cookies may impact on the functionality of the Websites. More information about managing cookies can be found at third-party information sites, such as [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

To prevent the information being collected by Google Analytics, please download and install the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on - <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>. To opt out of the use of advertising/targeting cookies, please visit [www.youronlinechoices.eu](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/).

**Web Beacons**

We also use web beacons provided by Google and Yandex. They are electronic images placed in the webpage code that help to track your activity on the Websites pages. Web beacons are used together with cookies to compile information about the usage of the Websites, improve their content and deliver relevant advertisings.

**Other Information**

**Third Party Sites**

Our Websites contain links to third party websites. We have no control over, and are not responsible for the content, privacy policies or reliability of such third-party connections. We encourage you to read the privacy policy of every website you visit.

**Minors Under the Age of 18**

Our Websites do not address children under the age of 18, and we do not knowingly collect personal data from children under the age of 18. Any personal information about a child under the age of 18 will be removed, if we become aware of it.

**Changes to This Privacy Policy**

We reserve the right to modify or supplement this Privacy Policy. The date of the latest update is indicated at the top of the text. We encourage you to periodically review this page to be aware of the recent data. Further use of our Websites means your acceptance of all the changes made.

**How to Contact Us**

Please send all your questions, complaints or comments regarding this Privacy Policy at [info@cadsofttools.com](mailto:info@cadsofttools.com).
